ENVIRONMENTAL SCIENTIST

Summary

An intermediate position in the field of environmental engineering & consulting I am an environmental scientist that is well educated with scientific and engineering background to deal with environmental problems and has been broadly trained to find out the perfect solutions to these problems. I am dedicated to make things change. Environmental quality assurance, Environmental sampling, Site investigation, Environmental monitoring and surveillance, Green building, Renewable energy, Sustainable design

Highlights

Experienced in AutoCAD, Google SketchUp, ArcGIS, and Photoshop

Experience

04/2016 to Current

Environmental Scientist Arcadis International i1/4 Guaynabo, PR

- Acts as environmental health and safety personnel for hazardous materials abatement projects and monitors construction activities for air quality and storm water compliance.
- Generates work plans for hazardous materials abatement projects and final reports for environmental quality assurance projects.
- Conducts data collection activities for all phases of hazardous material investigations including soil, groundwater, and air quality sampling
 Building surveys for hazardous materials including asbestos containing material, lead-based paints, and other environmental contaminants
 Completes sketches of building layouts for material investigations and sampling activities, and generates design drawings for abatement
 projects Performs air monitoring and inspections, soil and groundwater sampling during Environmental Quality Assurance (EQA) Projects,
 including monitoring of health and safety issues during asbestos and lead-based paint abatement projects and other industrial hygiene
 projects Performs Phase 1 and Phase 2 Environmental Audits.

06/2011 to 07/2012

Environmental Engineer Honda il/4 Irving

Created environmental installation proposals and construction plans of various types of diesel generator rooms Gathered site-specific data, reviewed site intake sheets provided by sales consultants, completed preliminary design, and drafted design using AutoCAD Worked cross functionally with sales consultants, project management and installation teams to satisfy clients' needs Addressed and corrected questions reported from checkers and inspectors Estimated pre-sale project.

03/2011 to 06/2011

Environmental Impact Assessment Specialist Huanya Environmental Protection Equipment Engineering Co. Ltd il/4 City

- Prepared environmental impact assessment report.
- Assisted and prepared regulatory approval and permitting applications.
- Arranged public participation and review.
- Provided practical and economic solutions to clients.

Education

May 2015

Master of Science: Environmental Management University of San Francisco (USF) il/4 City, State, USA Environmental Management 3.51 Thesis Title: An Exploratory Scenario for San Francisco to Become A Walking, Bicycling and Transit City

Jun. 2011

Bachelor of Science : Environmental Engineering South China Agricultural University (SCAU) i1/4 City , State , China Environmental Engineering 3.03

Certifications

ACCOMPLISHMENT University of San Francisco Climate Action Plan Food Waste Section Dec. 2014 Chinese Utility Model Patent (Publication No. CN201811461

Personal Information

607205737T) Environmental Protection Agency AHERA Asbestos Contractor/Supervisor (License: 40049 CS) Environmental Protection Agency AHERA Asbestos Building Inspector (License: ABII0725160009N10445) Hazardous Waste Operations and Emergency Response (HAZWOPER) 40-Hour Training

Languages

Proficient in Mandarin and Cantonese

Skille

Photoshop, AutoCAD, Cantonese, Chinese, clients, data collection, Dec, environmental health and safety, Mandarin, materials, monitors, paint, permitting, personnel, project management, proposals, Publication, quality, quality assurance, safety, sales, San, surveys Additional Information

State of California DOSH Certified Site Surveillance Technician (License: 607205737T) Environmental Protection Agency AHERA
Asbestos Contractor/Supervisor (License: 40049 CS) Environmental Protection Agency AHERA Asbestos Building Inspector (License:
ABII0725160009N10445) Hazardous Waste Operations and Emergency Response (HAZWOPER) 40-Hour Training